WUN C. CHIOU, JR.

Allen, TX | www.wunchiou.com

WEB DEVELOPER, DESIGNER, & EDUCATOR

I am a web developer with 10+ years experience designing and implementing websites, creating web graphics and video, and building web apps. I am well versed with modern authoring and scripting languages, content creation tools, management tools, and digital media. With experience in education & research, I also have excellent communication skills and can bridge the gap between the tech and business worlds. *Technical skills include:*

<u>Web:</u> HTML5, CSS3, Sass, JavaScript (pure / jQuery), Gulp, AJAX, PHP, Laravel, SQL, LAMP, Git

Apps: Dreamweaver, Photoshop, Fireworks, Flash, Acrobat, Camtasia, Vim, MS Office

OS: Mac OSX, Linux, Windows XP/7/8, iOS, Android

EDUCATION

M.S. Degree, Chemistry, UCLA, Los Angeles, CA, 2003

Research focus on computational physical chemistry First in my UCLA class to pass 5/5 physical chemistry cumulative exams Recipient of the US Dept. of Education's GAANN Fellowship, for first-year graduate achievement

B.S. Degree, Chemistry, UC BERKELEY, Berkeley, CA, 1998

With coursework and allied subject alignment in computer science

California Clear Teaching Credential, Secondary Chemistry, 2008 - Present

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

THE UNIVERSITY OF TEXAS AT DALLAS (utdallas.edu), Dallas, TX

Web Software Developer and Team Lead, 2015 - present

Led team of web developers in Research Information Systems to create websites and web software for the UT Dallas Office of Research and related research institutes and groups on campus.

- Created an easily-deployed, common development environment for the team, providing developers with a common set of tools
- Streamlined version control of web sites and applications with git and a development workflow.
- Implemented easy deployment method for sites and applications to various development, staging, and production servers.
- Developed web application for management of various research-related activities, including limited submissions, conflict of interest, and institutional review board.
- Developed websites for the department using WordPress with custom themes and plugins.
- Configured and managed web servers (Ubuntu, Red Hat Enterprise Linux).
- Worked together with University Information Resources to troubleshoot web software issues.
- Managed team of developers to deliver solutions to department needs.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE - CONTINUED

HIGH TECH LOS ANGELES CHARTER HIGH SCHOOL (ht-la.org), Los Angeles, CA

Science Teacher and Webmaster, 2004 - 2014

Instructed 10th – 12th grade students for the top-ranked college preparatory charter high school in CA. Also served as the school's webmaster, designing custom local web tools for students and teachers to use in their projects. Courses taught: *chemistry, environmental science, solar car, statistics, forensics, web programming, web design, advisory.*

- Built a custom student grading web app with a graphical data visualization of student presentation grades, data, and feedback using PHP, AJAX, SQL, and HTML5 canvas tools.
- Designed and managed the school's main website using the Drupal CMS with custom-styled theme utilizing extensive CSS3 and JavaScript/jQuery for fluid and aesthetic user experience.
- Implemented and managed a locally-hosted course management system (Moodle).
- Managed updates to both the system (via git) and the Linux server.
- Optimized web server and database for heavy concurrent access by 400 students.
- Ran technology professional development workshops and created tutorials for staff and students.
- Designed and implemented many cross-curricular projects. See http://mrchiou.wordpress.com
- Collaborated to fund and create a student-made solar-powered car. See http://ht-la.org/solarcar

MELIE BIANCO (meliebianco.com), Los Angeles, CA

Web Developer, 2003

Designed and launched a new catalog website for a startup, family-owned handbag and accessory company using dynamic HTML, PHP, and database programming.

- Created easy-to-use backend to update and add new products
- Photographed and included hundreds of handbag products
- Managed domain and web hosting

UNIVERSITY OF CALIFORNIA LOS ANGELES (www.chemistry.ucla.edu), Los Angeles, CA

Research Assistant / Graduate Student Instructor, 1999 – 2003

Worked concurrently during graduate education, doing research and serving as a teaching assistant for various undergraduate courses.

- Researched the chemistry of surfaces from first principles, running computer simulations and programming in Fortran with shell script analysis
- Taught discussion and lab sections for undergraduate courses in chemistry, graded student work, updated and created web-based resources for students.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE - CONTINUED

ABBOTT LABORATORIES, Columbus, OH

Physical Science Summer Intern, 1996 – 1996

Performed physical chemistry viscosity measurements for the Ross Products division of Abbott Laboratories. Studied physical characteristics of various products.

- Implemented an intranet publication of data sets from a database using HTML and VBScript.

PACIFIC MICROELECTRONICS/NETUSA.com, Mountain View, CA

Web Design Summer Intern, 1991 – 1995

Designed and developed complete web sites for clients at the dawn of the commercial Internet. Created covers for retail packaging of software products using Corel Draw.